const container = document.querySelector('.container');
const questionBox = document.querySelector('.question');
const choicesBox = document.querySelector('.choices');
const nextBtn = document.querySelector('.nextBtn');
const scoreCard = document.querySelector('.scoreCard');
const alert = document.querySelector('.alert');
const startBtn = document.querySelector('.startBtn');
const timer = document.querySelector('.timer');


// Make an array of objects that stores question, choices of question and answer
const quiz = [
    {
        question: "Q. How does Java Script store dates in objects of Date type?",
        choices: ["The number of days since January 1st, 1900", "The number of seconds since January 1st, 1970", "The number of milliseconds since January 1st, 1970", "The number of picoseconds since January 1st, 1970"],
        answer: "The number of milliseconds since January 1st, 1970"
    },
    {
        question: "Q. Which of the following is not a valid way to declare a function in JavaScript?",
        choices: ["function myFunction() {}", " let myFunction = function() {};", "myFunction: function() {}", "const myFunction = () => {};"],
        answer: "myFunction: function() {}"
    },
    {
        question: "Q. Which of the following is not a JavaScript data type?",
        choices: ["string", "boolean", "object", "float"],
        answer: "float"
    },
    {
        question: "Q. What is the purpose of the this keyword in JavaScript?",
        choices: ["It refers to the current function.", "It refers to the current object.", "It refers to the parent object.", " It is used for comments."],
        answer: "It refers to the current object."
    },
    {
        question: "Q. To insert a JavaScript into an HTML page, which tag is used?",
        choices: ["<script=â€™javaâ€™>", "<javascript>", "<script>", " <js>"],
        answer: "<script>"
    },
    {
        question: "Q. JavaScript ignores extra spaces",
        choices: ["True", "False"],
        answer: "True"
    },
    {
        question: "Q. Which attribute needs to be changed to make elements invisible?",
        choices: ["visibilty", "visible", "invisibility", "invisible"],
        answer: "visibilty"
    },
    {
        question: "Q. Which of the following is used to capture all click events in a window?",
        choices: ["window.captureEvents(Event.CLICK);", "window.routeEvents(Event.CLICK );", "window.handleEvents (Event.CLICK);", "window.raiseEvents(Event.CLICK );"],
        answer: "window.captureEvents(Event.CLICK);"
    },
    {
        question: "Q. Javascript is an object oriented language?",
        choices: ["True", "False"],
        answer: "False"
    },
    {
        question: "Q. Which of the ways below is incorrect of instantiating a date?",
        choices: ["new Date(dateString)", "new Date()", "new Date(seconds)", "new Date(year, month, day, hours, minutes, seconds, milliseconds)"],
        answer: "new Date(seconds)"
    }
];

// Making Variables
let currentQuestionIndex = 0;
let score = 0;
let quizOver = false;
let timeLeft = 15;
let timerID = null;

// Arrow Function to Show Questions
const showQuestions = () => {
    const questionDetails = quiz[currentQuestionIndex];
    questionBox.textContent = questionDetails.question;

    choicesBox.textContent = "";
    for (let i = 0; i < questionDetails.choices.length; i++) {
        const currentChoice = questionDetails.choices[i];
        const choiceDiv = document.createElement('div');
        choiceDiv.textContent = currentChoice;
        choiceDiv.classList.add('choice');
        choicesBox.appendChild(choiceDiv);

        choiceDiv.addEventListener('click', () => {
            if (choiceDiv.classList.contains('selected')) {
                choiceDiv.classList.remove('selected');
            }
            else {
                choiceDiv.classList.add('selected');
            }
        });
    }

    if(currentQuestionIndex < quiz.length){
        startTimer();
    }
}

// Function to check answers
const checkAnswer = () => {
    const selectedChoice = document.querySelector('.choice.selected');
    if (selectedChoice.textContent === quiz[currentQuestionIndex].answer) {
        // alert("Correct Answer!");
        displayAlert("Correct Answer!");
        score++;
    }
    else {
        // alert("Wrong answer");
        displayAlert(`Wrong Answer! ${quiz[currentQuestionIndex].answer} is the Correct Answer`);
    }
    timeLeft = 15;
    currentQuestionIndex++;
    if (currentQuestionIndex < quiz.length) {
        showQuestions();
    }
    else {
        stopTimer();
        showScore();
    }
}

// Function to show score
const showScore = () => {
    questionBox.textContent = "";
    choicesBox.textContent = "";
    scoreCard.textContent = `You Scored ${score} out of ${quiz.length}!`;
    displayAlert("You have completed this quiz!");
    nextBtn.textContent = "Play Again";
    quizOver = true;
    timer.style.display = "none";
}

// Function to Show Alert
const displayAlert = (msg) => {
    alert.style.display = "block";
    alert.textContent = msg;
    setTimeout(()=>{
        alert.style.display = "none";
    }, 2000);
}

// Function to Start Timer
const startTimer = () => {
    clearInterval(timerID); // Check for any exist timers
    timer.textContent = timeLeft;

    const countDown = ()=>{
        timeLeft--;
        timer.textContent = timeLeft;
        if(timeLeft === 0){
            const confirmUser = confirm("Time Up!!! Do you want to play the quiz again");
            if(confirmUser){
                timeLeft = 15;
                startQuiz();
            }
            else{
                startBtn.style.display = "block";
                container.style.display = "none";
                return;
            }
        }
    }
    timerID = setInterval(countDown, 1000);
}

// Function to Stop Timer
const stopTimer = () =>{
    clearInterval(timerID);
}

// Function to shuffle question
const shuffleQuestions = () =>{
    for(let i=quiz.length-1; i>0; i--){
        const j = Math.floor(Math.random() * (i+1));
        [quiz[i], quiz[j]] = [quiz[j], quiz[i]];
    }
    currentQuestionIndex = 0;
    showQuestions();
}

// Function to Start Quiz
const startQuiz = () =>{
    timeLeft = 15;
    timer.style.display = "flex";
    shuffleQuestions();
}

// Adding Event Listener to Start Button
startBtn.addEventListener('click', ()=>{
    startBtn.style.display = "none";
    container.style.display = "block";
    startQuiz();
});

nextBtn.addEventListener('click', () => {
    const selectedChoice = document.querySelector('.choice.selected');
    if (!selectedChoice && nextBtn.textContent === "Next") {
        // alert("Select your answer");
        displayAlert("Select your answer");
        return;
    }
    if (quizOver) {
        nextBtn.textContent = "Next";
        scoreCard.textContent = "";
        currentQuestionIndex = 0;
        quizOver = false;
        score = 0;
        startQuiz();
    }
    else {
        checkAnswer();
    }
});